Mitchell Watson

Phone (604)-355-0141

E-mail mitchellgwatson@gmail.com

Personal Website https://mitchellwatson.netlify.app/

LinkedIn mitchell-watson-1a553222a

Eager software development team member with 2+ years of post-secondary experience. Advanced in web-applications, Data Analytics/Machine Learning using Python, and Android mobile development using Java. During my free time, I enjoy weightlifting and staying physically fit.

Skills

Languages

Python, HTML, CSS, Java, JavaScript, C, C++, C#, R, SQL

Technologies

React.is, MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase, Linux, Android, Node.is, Express.is, Django, TensorFlow, PyTorch, Matplotlib, MatLab, Seaborn, Plotly, Pandas, Neural Networks, Numpy, Git, GitHub, Figma, MERN, REST, JUnit, XML, Excel, NoSQL, Big Data, JEST, GraphQL, AWS

Principles

Object Oriented Programming (OOP), Machine Learning (ML), Predictive/Data Analytics, Database Design/Management, Algorithms, Internet Service Architecture, Network Protocols, Business Communications, Agile Methodology

Work History

04/2023 - 05/2023 **QA Tester**

Super-Kamiokande – Vancouver, BC

- Built Unit and Automated Testing suites for program quality assurance
- Installed third-party simulation libraries onto academia cloud computing
- Refactored scientific research documentation and version control
- Apart of full-time, 5-week practicum

01/2023 – 04/2023 Junior Software Developer

Smart Microgrid Applied Research Team – Vancouver, BC

- Building React.js web-app for informing community about microgrids
- Provides real-time user interaction using custom web-app settings
- Database management and product designer
- Team utilized Trello, GitHub and Figma as part of agile, bi-weekly sprints

Grelhados Restaurant – Port Coquitlam, BC

- Demonstrated detailed, fast paced service
- Performed timely duties under pressure and time constraints
- Managed front of house operations and responsibilities

Education

09/2021 - 05/2023 Diploma, Computer Systems Technology

British Columbia Institute of Technology – Vancouver, BC

- Experienced with numerous front and back-end programming languages
- Specialization in Data Analytics and Machine Learning
- Developed web and mobile applications
- Graduated with Distinction and 87% GPA

09/2015 - 06/2020 High School Diploma

Ecole Riverside Secondary School – Port Coquitlam, BC

- Graduated with Gold Cord and Honors
- Received Dual Dogwood French Immersion Diploma
- Completed B2 DELF French assessment
- Praised for both individual and group participation on projects and assignments

Interests

- Weight training
- Active Living
- Tech
- Food
- Music